Frederick J. Pohl Papers
Frederick J. Pohl Papers
1944-1967.
Pohl, Frederick Julius, 1889-1991.
0.5 linear ft.
The papers of the American author of books about the pre-Columbian exploration and discovery of the New World contain correspondence (1944-1963, 1967), mostly of Hjalmar Holand; notes; and clippings.
149524
Biographical History
Frederick Julius Pohl was born in Durham, New York, in 1889. He received his bachelor's degree from Amherst College and his master's degree from Columbia University. Pohl's books include The Sinclair Expedition to Nova Scotia in 1398 (1950); The Lost Discovery (1952); The Vikings on Cape Cod (1957); Atlantic Crossings Before Columbus (1961); The Viking Explorers (1966); and Amerigo Vespucci (1966). He was a contributor to Rhode Island History, New England Quarterly, American-Scandinavian Review, Archaeology, and Shakespeare Newsletter. He died in 1991.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The papers of Frederick Julius Pohl consist of Correspondence, Manuscripts and Published material. Correspondence (13 folders) spans 1944-1963 and 1967 and includes letters to and letters from Mr. Pohl, interfiled and arranged alphabetically by name. Manuscripts (1 folder) contains notes written by Mr. Pohl in 1947 and 1949 and others that are undated. Published material (2 folders) consists of newspaper articles from 1948 and 1963.
Subject and Genre Headings
Historians; Holand, Hjalmar Rued, 1872-1963.; Pohl, Frederick Julius, 1889-1991.; Authors, American.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Authors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - G-Howard Holand
    - 1947, 1963, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Hjalmar Holand
    - 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946 (Box 1)
    - 1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 1)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Hough-R
    - 1946-1948, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - S-T and unidentified
    - 1947, 1951-1952, 1954, 1956, 1960-1961, undated (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Notes
    - 1947, 1949, undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Newspaper articles about H.R. Holand
    - 1963 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper articles by
    - 1948 (Box 1)